<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!--
   Licensed to the Apache Software Foundation (ASF) under one or more
   contributor license agreements.  See the NOTICE file distributed with
   this work for additional information regarding copyright ownership.
   The ASF licenses this file to You under the Apache License, Version 2.0
   (the "License"); you may not use this file except in compliance with
   the License.  You may obtain a copy of the License at

       http://www.apache.org/licenses/LICENSE-2.0

   Unless required by applicable law or agreed to in writing, software
   distributed under the License is distributed on an "AS IS" BASIS,
   WITHOUT WARRANTIES OR CONDITIONS OF ANY KIND, either express or implied.
   See the License for the specific language governing permissions and
   limitations under the License.
-->
<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Canoo WebTest Maven Plugin</title>
    <author>Siegfried Goeschl</author>
  </properties>

  <body>
    <section name="Introduction">
      <p> The webtest-maven-plugin allows running <a href="http://webtest.canoo.com">Canoo
          Webtest</a> within a Maven 2 build but you might have guessed that already. Furthermore
        the plugin provides some additional syntactic sugar such as <ul>
          <li>run the tests in a loop</li>
          <li>force a build error even when errors and failures are explictely ignored</li>
          <li>check the result file for certain strings and fail if they exists</li>
        </ul>
      </p>
      <subsection name="Plugin Installation">
        <p> The plugin is currently hosted as sandbox plugin at <a href="http://mojo.codehaus.org">
          Codehaus Mojo</a> therefore no regular release is currently available. Uptodate
          snapshots are being deployed on <a href="http://snapshots.repository.codehaus.org">
          Codehaus Snapshot Repository</a> regulary.
        </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Getting some examples">
        <p> The hardest part is making the first successful steps when being new to Canoo Webtest
          and/or Maven. For some inspiration what you can do (e.g. JavaScript execution, embedding
          Groovy steps, testing PDF documents) check out the integration tests under
          ./src/test/itX</p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Using Canoo WebTest with M1">
        <p> A M1 plugin is available at <a href="http://maven-plugins.sourceforge.net"
            >http://maven-plugins.sourceforge.net</a></p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Running tests in a loop">
        <p> This is quite handy when you do load tests in parallel - in the background you run your
          webtests to ensure that the functional tests still work under high load. The loop exits
          after a number of configurable iterations or when encountering the first problem. </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Force a build error">
        <p> A common problem with Continous Integration is the fact that you want run all tests and
          not stop after the first problem. Running all tests means also to finish the build (e.g.
          generating test reports) before you force a build failure - this is implemented in <a
            href="verify-result-mojo.html"> webtest:verify-result</a>. </p>
      </subsection>
      <subsection name="Checking the result files">
        <p> Another common problem are server processing errors behind a shiny HTTP 200 result code,
          e.g. "An application error has occured" plus two screen meter of stack trace showing off
          all your implementation details. So if you fail to detect this magic messages in your test
          you have a problem while adding those checks to all tests makes them much harder to
          maintain. Therefore <a href="verify-filecontent-mojo.html">webtest:verify-filecontent</a>
          is your friend. </p>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </body>
</document>
